<page>
    <title>Wikipedia:Mediation Cabal/Cases/2006-05-15 Talk:Calvary Chapel</title>
    <ns>4</ns>
    <id>5151475</id>
    <revision>
      <id>453963985</id>
      <parentid>453851709</parentid>
      <timestamp>2011-10-04T20:16:07Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>SteveBot</username>
        <id>7048732</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor />
      <comment>subst depreceated template, gen fixes using [[Project:AWB|AWB]] (7794)</comment>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve">== Mediation Case: 2006-05-15 Talk:Calvary Chapel ==

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center; margin: 0 10% 1em 10%; border: 1px solid #aaa;&quot;&gt;
Please observe [[Wikipedia:Etiquette]] and [[WP:TP#Etiquette|Talk Page Etiquette]] in disputes. If you submit complaints or insults your edits are likely to be removed by the mediator, any other [[WP:REFACTOR|refactoring]] of the mediation case by anybody but the mediator is likely to be reverted. If you are not satisfied with the mediation procedure please submit your complaints to [[Wikipedia talk:Mediation Cabal]].
&lt;/div&gt;


=== Request Information===
: '''Request made by:''' [[User:David L Rattigan|David L Rattigan]] 10:41, 15 May 2006 (UTC)

; ''Where is the issue taking place?''
: [[Talk:Calvary Chapel]]

; ''Who's involved?''
: Myself, anonymous users [http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Special:Contributions&amp;target=66.177.178.5 66.177.178.5] and (recently) [http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Special:Contributions&amp;target=70.89.12.50 70.89.12.50]

; ''What's going on?''
: I tagged the [[Talk:Calvary Chapel]] page with a template for [[Wikipedia:WikiProject Charismatic Christianity]]. It has been removed three times (and replaced by me). I have justified the decision ''with reference to an academic work'', but the other user continues to remove it for purely POV reasons, ie that s/he has made no attempt to justify.

; ''What would you like to change about that?
: Very simply, I would like an admin/mediator to step in and make a ruling on it. I don't think it's a tough issue to resolve - it just needs someone with a bit of authority to tell the other person to quit deleting the template, otherwise we'll just be reversing each other's edits till kingdom come.

; ''Would you be willing to be a mediator yourself, and accept a mediation assignment in a different case?''
:Yes, no problem.

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center; margin: 0 10% 1em 10%; border: 1px solid #aaa;&quot;&gt;
:: This is, following the [[Categorical Imperative]], the idea that you might want to do
:: what you expect others to do. You don't have to, of course, that's why it's a question.
&lt;/div&gt;
: ...

=== Mediator response ===

Contact made on articles talk page.  Seems like a simple disagreement which should be resolved by agreement on sources and consultation of the wikiproject in question. [[User:kcordina|Kcordina]] &lt;sup&gt; [[User talk:Kcordina|Talk]] &lt;/sup&gt; 08:11, 16 May 2006 (UTC)

Issue resolved by opening discussion. Closing case [[User:kcordina|Kcordina]] &lt;sup&gt; [[User talk:Kcordina|Talk]] &lt;/sup&gt; 10:27, 18 May 2006 (UTC)

=== Evidence ===

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center; margin: 0 10% 1em 10%; border: 1px solid #aaa;&quot;&gt;
Please report evidence in this section with &lt;nowiki&gt;{{&lt;/nowiki&gt;[[Wikipedia:Mediation_Cabal/Evidence]]&lt;nowiki&gt;}}&lt;/nowiki&gt; for misconduct and &lt;nowiki&gt;{{&lt;/nowiki&gt;[[Wikipedia:Mediation_Cabal/Evidence3RR]]&lt;nowiki&gt;}}&lt;/nowiki&gt; for [[WP:3RR|3RR]] violations. If you need
help ask a [[Wikipedia:Mediation_Cabal#Cabalists|mediator]] or an [[WP:AMA|advocate]]. Evidence is of limited use in mediation as the mediator has no authority. Providing some evidence may, however, be useful in making both sides act more civil.
&lt;br&gt;
'''[[Wikipedia:Etiquette]]''': ''Although it's understandably difficult in a heated argument, if the other party is not as civil as you'd like them to be, make sure to be more civil than him or her, not less.''
&lt;/div&gt;

=== Compromise offers ===

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center; margin: 0 10% 1em 10%; border: 1px solid #aaa;&quot;&gt;
This section is for listing and discussing compromise offers.
&lt;/div&gt;

=== Comments by others ===

{{Wikipedia:Mediation_Cabal/Comments_Section}}

=== Discussion ===
It would be my view that the scope of the Charismatic project is that it does not just encompass the Pentecostal/Charismatic movement &quot;proper&quot;, but rather all Christian movements that embrace (in a large or smalll way) the Charismatic gifts, and as such, Calvary Chapel would form part of that [[User:Jaems|Jaems]] 11:54, 17 May 2006 (UTC)
:Thanks, [[User:Kcordina|Kcordina]]. Looks like the person who initially stirred up the problem has a history of trying to force a POV on the article anyway, and s/he seems to have disappeared now. Thanks for opening things up. [[User:David L Rattigan|David L Rattigan]] 10:58, 18 May 2006 (UTC)

[[Category:Wikipedia Medcab closed cases]]</text>
      <sha1>cumz697j7987cnmxv8qn3wzbbnx2lo9</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
