<page>
    <title>Talk:India</title>
    <ns>1</ns>
    <id>639109</id>
    <revision>
      <id>928691344</id>
      <parentid>928673434</parentid>
      <timestamp>2019-12-01T01:09:01Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Lowercase sigmabot III</username>
        <id>17518500</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor />
      <comment>Archiving 1 discussion(s) to [[Talk:India/Archive 47]]) (bot</comment>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text xml:space="preserve">{{Talk header}}
{{Vital article|topic=Geography|level=3|class=FA}}
{{FAQ|collapsed=yes}}
{{Indian English}}
{{Article history
|action1=FAC
|action1date=22:24, 16 Sep 2004
|action1link=Wikipedia:Featured article candidates/India
|action1result=promoted
|action1oldid=5945311
|action2=FAR
|action2date=11 Apr 2005
|action2link=Wikipedia:Featured article removal candidates/India/archive1
|action2result=kept
|action2oldid=12191859
|action3=FAR
|action3date=15:45, 6 May 2006
|action3link=Wikipedia:Featured article removal candidates/India/archive2
|action3result=kept
|action3oldid=51836931
|action4=FAR
|action4date=14:15, 28 July 2011
|action4link=Wikipedia:Featured article review/India/archive2
|action4result=kept
|action4oldid=441811169
|maindate=December 3, 2004
|maindate2=October 2, 2019
|currentstatus=FA
|otd1date=2004-08-15
|otd1oldid=5256057
|otd2date=2005-08-15
|otd2oldid=21044027
|otd3date=2011-08-15
|otd3oldid=444882019
|otd4date=2012-11-26
|otd4oldid=524820236
}}
{{GOCE|user=Twofingered Typist|date=21 September 2019}}
{{WikiProjectBannerShell|collapsed=yes|1=

{{WikiProject India|class=FA|importance=Top|portal=yes}}
{{WikiProject South Asia|class=FA|importance=Top}}
{{WikiProject Asia|class=FA|importance=Top}}
{{WikiProject Countries|class=FA|importance=Top}}
{{WikiProject Spoken Wikipedia|India.ogg}}
{{WP1.0|v0.5=pass|importance=Top|class=FA|category=Geography|VA=yes|coresup=yes}}}}
{{Press|collapsed=yes|date=17 August 2009 |url= http://www.telegraph.co.uk/technology/wikipedia/6043534/The-50-most-viewed-Wikipedia-articles-in-2009-and-2008.html |title=The 50 most-viewed Wikipedia articles in 2009 and 2008 |org=[[The Daily Telegraph]] |date2=27 August 2009 |url2=http://www.telegraph.co.uk/technology/wikipedia/6099890/Wikipedia-Top-20-people-places-film-and-technology-articles.html|title2=Wikipedia: Top 20 people, places, film and technology articles |org2=[[The Daily Telegraph]] |author2=James Steyn |date3=4 July 2015 |url3=http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/The-vandals-of-Wiki/articleshow/47941452.cms |title3=The Vandals of Wiki |org3=[[The Times of India]] |author3=Sandhya Soman}}
{{Ds/talk notice|ipa|long}} 

{{Outline of knowledge coverage|India}}
{{Annual readership |width=570 |days=182}}
{{Section sizes}}
{{Top 25 report
  | August 11, 2013
  | October 20, 2013 | until | November 24, 2013
  | December 8, 2013
  | December 29, 2013 | until | January 19, 2014
}}
{{auto archiving notice|bot=lowercase sigmabot III|age=30}}
{{User:HBC Archive Indexerbot/OptIn |target=/Archive index |mask=/Archive &lt;#&gt; |leading_zeros=0 |indexhere=yes }}
{{User:MiszaBot/config
|archiveheader = {{Aan}}
|maxarchivesize = 150K
|counter = 47
|minthreadsleft = 10
|minthreadstoarchive = 1
|algo = old(30d)
|archive = Talk:India/Archive %(counter)d
}}

== Reordering superlatives sentence ==

A sentence in the lead paragraph currently reads {{tq|It is the [[List of countries and dependencies by area|seventh-largest]] country by area, the [[List of countries and dependencies by population|second-most populous]] country, and the most populous [[democracy]] in the world.}} I propose that it be changed to {{tq|It is the [[List of countries and dependencies by population|second-most populous]] country, the most populous [[democracy]], and the [[List of countries and dependencies by area|seventh-largest]] country by area.}} This reordering helps to emphasize the traits that make India unique by listing them first. (In very basic terms, when one thinks of India, &quot;lots of people&quot; comes to mind before &quot;lots of land.&quot;) I understand that listing area first has been a long-standing norm, but I think we ought to adapt to the noteworthy elements by country — readers won't take up pitchforks if we list population first here but area first for [[Russia]]. Thoughts, everyone? [[User:Sdkb|Sdkb]] ([[User talk:Sdkb|talk]]) 01:54, 3 October 2019 (UTC)

:I think that &quot;It is the [[List of countries and dependencies by population|second-most populous]] country, the [[List of countries and dependencies by area|seventh-largest]] country by area, and the most populous [[democracy]] in the world.&quot; is a better option, as population and area are one of the primary characteristics for a country (and population matters more in the case of India). [[User:Bharatiya29|&lt;font color=&quot;#FF9933&quot;&gt;Bharatiya&lt;/font&gt;]][[User talk:Bharatiya29|&lt;font color=&quot;#138808&quot;&gt;29&lt;/font&gt;]] 19:17, 3 October 2019 (UTC)

::{{re|Fowler&amp;fowler}} Since you were the one calling for consensus before this change gets implemented: do you have any objection to or preference between my/Bharatiya29's proposals and the status quo? [[User:Sdkb|Sdkb]] ([[User talk:Sdkb|talk]]) 04:54, 6 October 2019 (UTC)
:::It sounds ridiculous.  Silly.  Awful.  I'm returning to my vacation.  Consensus does not mean that two people can write claptrap and agree with each other. I'm returning to my vacation, like I just said. [[User:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#B8860B&quot;&gt;Fowler&amp;amp;fowler&lt;/span&gt;]][[User talk:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#708090&quot;&gt;«Talk»&lt;/span&gt;]] 05:24, 6 October 2019 (UTC)

::::{{re|Fowler&amp;fowler}} Whoa! Don't know how a minor suggestion like this can warrant such an absurd response, but it will be better if you do your part towards keeping this discussion civil. Calling others' opinion &quot;claptrap&quot; is kinda unbecoming for an experienced contributor like you. {{re|Sdkb}} Since this impacts the lead of a highly important article, I suggest you to initiate an RfC regarding this. [[User:Bharatiya29|&lt;font color=&quot;#FF9933&quot;&gt;Bharatiya&lt;/font&gt;]][[User talk:Bharatiya29|&lt;font color=&quot;#138808&quot;&gt;29&lt;/font&gt;]] 17:11, 6 October 2019 (UTC)
{{od}}
FWIIW, I prefer the current order. Other than the logical sequencing, the most important thing is what we end with, not what we begin with. -- [[User:Kautilya3|Kautilya3]] ([[User talk:Kautilya3|talk]]) 18:45, 6 October 2019 (UTC)

* I '''prefer the current version''' {{tq|It is the [[List of countries and dependencies by area|seventh-largest]] country by area, the [[List of countries and dependencies by population|second-most populous]] country, and the most populous [[democracy]] in the world}}. If I remember correctly from my history textbooks, I have always seen the area mentioned first and then the population/largest democracy. I did a search for Google books just now (&quot;india the seventh largest country&quot; without quotes) and checked the first new pages. A significant majority of the results state the area first and then the population.--[[User:DreamLinker|DreamLinker]] ([[User talk:DreamLinker|talk]]) 14:43, 7 October 2019 (UTC)
* Keep the original version. [[User:Darwin Naz|Darwin Naz]] ([[User talk:Darwin Naz|talk]]) 23:21, 30 October 2019 (UTC)

== Comprise in the meaning of constitute is perfectly legitimate usage ==

{{ping|Smjg}} It goes back more than two centuries:

[[Oxford English Dictionary]]: (OED)  Comprise  8b  To constitute, make up, compose.

#1794   W. Paley View Evidences Christianity I. i. ix. 212   The propositions which comprise the several heads of our testimony.
#1850   W. S. Harris Rudim. Magn. iv. 73   These substances which we have termed diamagnetic..and which comprise a very extensive class of bodies.
#1907   H. E. Santee Anat. Brain &amp; Spinal Cord (1908) iii. 237   The fibres comprising the zonal layer have four sources of origin.
#1925   Brit. Jrnl. Radiology 30 148   The various fuses etc. comprising the circuit.
#1950   M. Peake Gormenghast xiv. 86   Who, by the way, do comprise the Staff these latter days?
#1959   Chambers's Encycl. XIII. 653/1   These fibres also comprise the main element in scar tissue.
#1969   W. Hooper in C. S. Lewis Sel. Lit. Ess. p. xix   These essays together with those contained in this volume comprise the total of C. S. Lewis's essays on literature.
#1969   N. Perrin Dr. Bowdler's Legacy (1970) i. 20   As to who comprised this new reading public, Jeffrey..guessed in 1812 that there were 20,000 upper-class readers in Great Britain.
(Hide quotations)
 
 
c. passive. To be composed of, to consist of.
#1874   Art of Paper-Making ii. 10   Thirds, or Mixed, are comprised of either or both of the above.
#1928   Daily Tel. 17 July 10/7   The voluntary boards of management, comprised..of very zealous and able laymen.
#1964   E. Palmer tr. A. Martinet Elements Gen. Linguistics i. 28   Many of these words are comprised of monemes.
#1970   Nature 27 June 1206/2   Internally, the chloroplast is comprised of a system of flattened membrane sacs.

Webster's Unabridged:

Comprise (v): 
5a :  to consist of :  be made up of
&lt;the fortress comprises many miles of entrenchment and well-hidden artillery positions&gt;
&lt;the thirty-five essays it comprises … are mostly reprinted from previous collections — Harry Levin&gt;
b :  to make up :  constitute
&lt;the receipts … comprised the fifth-largest gate in boxing history — John Lardner&gt;

May I respectfully suggest that you not change that sentence until you have gained consensus for it on this talk page.  [[User:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#B8860B&quot;&gt;Fowler&amp;amp;fowler&lt;/span&gt;]][[User talk:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#708090&quot;&gt;«Talk»&lt;/span&gt;]] 18:28, 5 October 2019 (UTC)


Those two require subscriptions.  But here is one available freely online:

[https://www.ldoceonline.com/dictionary/comprise Longman Dictionary of Contemporary English]

2 [transitive] to form part of a larger group of people or things SYN constitute, make up
Women comprise a high proportion of part-time workers.  [[User:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#B8860B&quot;&gt;Fowler&amp;amp;fowler&lt;/span&gt;]][[User talk:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#708090&quot;&gt;«Talk»&lt;/span&gt;]] 18:49, 5 October 2019 (UTC)

Here's another: [https://www.collinsdictionary.com/dictionary/english/comprise Collins/COBUILD Advanced English Dictionary]:

2. verb
The things or people that comprise something are the parts or members that form it.

Examples: The proposals exclude three of the four nations comprising the UK.. [VERB noun]
Women comprise 44% of hospital medical staff. [VERB noun]

Synonyms: make up, form, constitute, compose   [[User:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#B8860B&quot;&gt;Fowler&amp;amp;fowler&lt;/span&gt;]][[User talk:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#708090&quot;&gt;«Talk»&lt;/span&gt;]] 18:56, 5 October 2019 (UTC)

:Not sure why anybody would have an issue with &quot;Comprises&quot;, I certainly use it regularly in my real life work. [[User:MilborneOne|MilborneOne]] ([[User talk:MilborneOne|talk]]) 19:13, 5 October 2019 (UTC)

:: {{reply|Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|MilborneOne}} So what?  How is the article improved by using this word rather than any of the alternatives?  Furthermore, where is the consensus to use this word rather than any of the alternatives?
:: MilborneOne, when you say you &quot;certainly use it regularly&quot;, with which meaning do you use it?  The meaning &quot;be made up of&quot;, or the opposite of this?
:: People don't have issues with the word.  People have issues with the use of it to mean &quot;make up&quot; or similar.  There are a number of reasons for this:
::* It is diametrically opposite to the traditional, literal meaning of the word, which remains undisputedly correct.
::* It is rooted in confusion between &quot;comprise&quot; and other similar words like &quot;compose&quot; and &quot;constitute&quot;.
::* It makes no sense for a word to have two meanings that are diametric opposites of each other, and even less sense when one of these meanings is a duplicate of one for which we already have one or more perfectly good words.
::* Many of us are taught that it is just not the meaning of the word.  As such, it is not &quot;perfectly&quot; legitimate as you are claiming.
:: I shall also refer you to [[Wikipedia:Manual of Style#Contested vocabulary]].  The link to [[List of English words with disputed usage]] there shows that to avoid using a word with a meaning that is disputed is part of the spirit, if not the letter, of what it's saying. — [[User:Smjg|Smjg]] ([[User talk:Smjg|talk]]) 21:05, 5 October 2019 (UTC)

::: Furthermore, as a rule, dictionaries reflect usage.  That a dictionary lists a certain word with a certain meaning doesn't automatically mean it's a correct usage of the word. — [[User:Smjg|Smjg]] ([[User talk:Smjg|talk]]) 21:07, 5 October 2019 (UTC)

:::: I am not sure where this is coming from, I use the word like loads of other people like &quot;The Thing comprises a, b, c and d&quot;, in normal use of English it is perfectly understood and I am not aware that it means anything else. It is unlikely to be confused with anything else as in normal usage it only has one use. In the end it does the job says what it means and I see no reason to change it. [[User:MilborneOne|MilborneOne]] ([[User talk:MilborneOne|talk]]) 23:15, 5 October 2019 (UTC)

:::::Pinging WP's [https://medium.com/backchannel/meet-the-ultimate-wikignome-10508842caad resident expert] on &quot;comprised&quot;, {{u|Giraffedata}}. - [[User:Sdkb|Sdkb]] ([[User talk:Sdkb|talk]]) 04:48, 6 October 2019 (UTC)
{{od}} {{re|Smjg}} Who's residence?  Not this article's.  

Here is a history lesson.  You will agree that &quot;comprise&quot; in the sense of &quot;constitute&quot; (hereafter CITSOC), or &quot;make up,&quot; or &quot;form&quot;  is documented in dictionaries.   The evidence is overwhelming that CITSOC was used without dispute or controversy during the 18th and 19th centuries.  

Unfortunately, early in the 20th, at the conclusion of [[World War I|the war to end all wars]] (hereasfter WTEAW),  [[Henry Watson Fowler|half my namesake]], mourning the loss of the other half of my namesake from [[tuberculosis|consumption]] contracted in the selfsame WTEAW, which in any case had not lived up to its name, forgot the dicta of their [[The King's English|pre-WTEAW effort]], ''viz.'': &lt;blockquote&gt; Prefer the familiar word to the far-fetched. &lt;br/&gt; Prefer the concrete word to the abstract.&lt;br/&gt;Prefer the single word to the circumlocution. &lt;br/&gt; Prefer the short word to the long.&lt;br/&gt; Prefer the Saxon word to the Romance. (hereafter PPPPP)&lt;/blockquote&gt;
and began to  wage a WTEAW of words (hereafter WTEAWOW) against CITSOC in his [[A Dictionary of Modern English Usage|eponymous style guide]].  For half a century, thereafter, others such as the plain-speaking [[Ernest Gowers]], also waged WTEAWOW against CITSOC.  However, with the onset of detente, rapprochement, and the Fall of the Berlin Wall, WTEAWOW against CITSOC became a spent force.  The pent-up yearnings of the people to employ CITSOC in the speech and writing were released and the [https://www.google.com/search?tbm=bks&amp;q=%22comprises+the+bulk+of%22+ evidence is again overwhelming] for CITSOC.  So where are we now? We could write, &quot;India makes up the bulk of the Indian subcontinent.&quot;  This would be in line with PPPPP.  But that would sound too ordinary, befitting more the Simple Wikipedia.  But, of the two sleeping dogs, comprise and constitute, one has precedence in the article, by many years, which is a strong case for letting them lie.  I'm now returning to my vacation, as I've already stated twice upstairs.  Best regards, [[User:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#B8860B&quot;&gt;Fowler&amp;amp;fowler&lt;/span&gt;]][[User talk:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#708090&quot;&gt;«Talk»&lt;/span&gt;]] 05:18, 6 October 2019 (UTC)

:Wow, such a lot of work proving what is not disputed: that CITSOC is in common usage today, and has been used for hundreds of years.  But the claim that the evidence is overwhelming that it was used without dispute or controversy during the 18th and 19th centuries needs a lot more proof.  I've seen no evidence at all of the absence of dispute or controversy, and I have been studying the word &quot;comprise&quot; for decades, with the help of dozens of people who defend its secondary meanings.  I've actually looked more at &quot;comprise&quot; used to mean &quot;compose&quot; rather that &quot;constitute&quot;, but it's the same question.  And the most important evidence of its historical acceptance is the actual counts of usage in historical documents, which show CITSOC has been used since at least the 1700s, but at a very low and stable level, rising only in the 1960s.  That makes it clear to me that while people were making the mistake for hundreds of years, other people were correcting it all along.  A writer might use CITSOC, but his teacher or editor would correct it and he wouldn't do it anymore.  Kind of like using &quot;effect&quot; to mean &quot;affect&quot; today.  The 1960s brought a laissez-faire culture where it was not cool to force people to conform to arbitrary standards, so corrections like this declined.
:But this is all kind of beside the point, because the fact that millions of English writers think CITSOC is just plain incorrect means its legitimacy must be something less than perfect, even if all those writers are basically wrong.  And when there are alternatives that don't have such opposition, why would we even waste our time trying to defend CITSOC?
:I actually gave up arguing about correctness and legitimacy of English usage long ago; it's kind of fun, but way too abstract, since there is no official specification of English.  So I won't say CITSOC is not perfectly legitimate, but I ''will'' say it's not the best possible wording for a Wikipedia article.  [[User:Giraffedata|Bryan Henderson (giraffedata)]] ([[User talk:Giraffedata|talk]]) 07:37, 6 October 2019 (UTC)
::{{ping|Giraffedata}}  Under more congenial circumstances, bending the elbow with an [[India Pale Ale]] for instance, I might have agreed with your last statement, but (and there's always that &quot;but&quot;) this is a tired old page (to be precise the [[Special:MostRevisions|16th most tired old on Wikipedia]]) the shifting sands of whose phrasing drafted in such shifting mysteries of edits that even the tired old hawks of usage, such as I, who wheel overhead, are unable to watch with the eyes that are commonly attributed to us.  The full sentence of the dispute is: &quot;India comprises the bulk of the Indian subcontinent, lying atop the [[Indian Plate|Indian tectonic plate]], a part of the [[Indo-Australian Plate]].&quot;  Although I had written the Geography section a long time ago, this didn't sound like something I could have written.  At first glance, it seems too jerky, too terse, for my taste.  At second glance, the bigger problem is not the &quot;comprise,&quot; but the participle phrase, &quot;lying atop the Indian tectonic plate.  It is not clear that it applies to &quot;India&quot; or the subcontinent. (That the subcontinent lies entirely on the Indian Plate is sometimes disputed.)  So I delved, ... and found [https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=India&amp;oldid=431432376#Geography this edit of  2011], which read, &quot;India, the major portion of the Indian subcontinent, lies atop the [[Indian Plate|Indian tectonic plate]], a minor plate within the [[Indo-Australian Plate]].&quot;  That sounds more like something I would have written. How did the sentence change?  Why was &quot;minor&quot; taken out?  These are mysteries that I have learned not to probe.  But the sentence in its present condition cannot stand.  How about changing it to:  &quot;India makes up the bulk of the Indian subcontinent. It lies atop the [[Indian Plate|Indian tectonic plate]], a part of the [[Indo-Australian Plate]].&quot;  Sure, they are simple sentences, but a reader has a lot of new information to process. (&quot;Make up,&quot; is also higher up the totem pole in the 5Ps; &quot;comprise&quot; is French and &quot;constitute&quot; Latin.) I will leave it there.  My better half is reminding me again that I'm on vacation, and that this means doing the things that are the hallmarks of a vacation. So I won't return to check.  But make whatever edit you think is judicious.  I will look at it three months later.  (Also pinging {{ping|MilborneOne}} {{ping|Smjg}} {{ping|Sdkb}} {{ping|Kautilya3}}) Best [[User:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#B8860B&quot;&gt;Fowler&amp;amp;fowler&lt;/span&gt;]][[User talk:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#708090&quot;&gt;«Talk»&lt;/span&gt;]] 13:31, 6 October 2019 (UTC)
:Well, that sentence (which I'm seeing for the first time) is actually an acceptable use of &quot;comprise&quot; in its primary, undisputed meaning, though for a slightly different meaning (in emphasis only) from the &quot;constitute&quot; sense.  And that's all the more reason to use something else if we really want to say constitute.  One can think of a country as including territory, so India can comprise most of the subcontinent in that sense.  I have used it hundreds of times that way in Wikipedia.  We can also think of a land mass as including the countries whose territory is part of the land mass, so India can constitute most of the subcontinent too.  So do we want to say India uses up the subcontinent or generates it?  I like &quot;makes up&quot;, except I'm not crazy about a single thing making up something.  I'm going to try &quot;accounts for&quot; instead.  Let's see how that wears for three months.  :-) [[User:Giraffedata|Bryan Henderson (giraffedata)]] ([[User talk:Giraffedata|talk]]) 03:42, 8 October 2019 (UTC)

:: Just realised I hadn't got back to you guys on this.  For the record, until the late 1990s, as far as I can remember, I hadn't even heard of CITSOC (as in hadn't even heard of the phenomenon, let alone the acronym), even among other words with opposite meanings that I had heard being confused with each other like plug/socket and lend/borrow (mostly by non-native English speakers).  I think the first I ever heard of &quot;comprise&quot; being used to mean anything other than &quot;be made up of&quot; was in Word 6's grammar checker.  I'm not sure now how exactly I came across it.  It was probably a case where the grammar checker couldn't work out whether I was using the word correctly and was just asking me to check.
:: But I realise this is a tricky case.  But &quot;accounts for&quot; seems to me better than &quot;comprises&quot; or &quot;constitutes&quot; or anything else I can think of.  So if there's no objection, I say let &quot;accounts for&quot; stand.
:: Thank you very much [[User:Giraffedata|Giraffedata]] for your input on this. — [[User:Smjg|Smjg]] ([[User talk:Smjg|talk]]) 13:24, 30 November 2019 (UTC)
:::Just a clarification about the acronym CITSOC: Fowler&amp;fowler apparently made that up just for use in this discussion.  I'm probably the world's leading expert on the word &quot;comprise&quot; and the controversy over its usage, and I've never heard the acronym before.  I like it, though; the issue is widely enough discussed that it probably ought to have a name.  [[User:Giraffedata|Bryan Henderson (giraffedata)]] ([[User talk:Giraffedata|talk]]) 22:31, 30 November 2019 (UTC)

== Declining satus of women in Mauryan and Gupta emprie ==

It is mentioned in the second paragraph that &quot;Early political consolidations gave rise to the loose-knit Maurya and Gupta Empires based in the Ganges Basin.[27] Their collective era was suffused with wide-ranging creativity,[28] but also marked by the declining status of women,[29]&quot;. I think its baised assessment not appropriate because satus of women is lower to men in majority parts of the world until 20th century, women got voting rights in US and UK only in1920s. But it is not mentioned in their Wikipedia pages that until 1920s those countries have lower status for their women than men. It was in the very human evolution that women were declined equal status with men. 

And can it be proved that before Mauryan and Gupta period the women had a better satus than in the Mauryan and Gupta period? The proof for that same should be added as a reference, if not the statement be removed for the better. [[User:BodduLokesh|BodduLokesh]] ([[User talk:BodduLokesh|talk]]) 19:56, 14 October 2019 (UTC)

And when it is not mentioned in Wikipedia pages of any other country, selectively mentioning in the India wikipedia page and that too mentioned that in a peirod 2500 years ago seems abaurd. And reference required that women enjoyed superior/equal status to men before Mauryan and Gupta period, if not the statement be removed. Showing proof that low status of women existed in Gupta and Mauryan era says only that it existed in their era, it doesn't say whether it existed before them or not. So, proof is required that women are not treated lower to men before Mauryan and Gupta era, if not general assumption can be made there existed same situation for women even before Mauryan and Gupta period if this assumption/argument is not negated with proof. [[User:BodduLokesh|BodduLokesh]] ([[User talk:BodduLokesh|talk]]) 20:05, 14 October 2019 (UTC)
:Please don't engage in long diatribes.  Read the cited sources. The condition of women in India deteriorated during the Maurya and Gupta periods.  That means it became worse:  &lt;blockquote&gt;Political consolidations gave rise to the loose-knit [[Maurya Empire|Maurya]] and [[Gupta Empire|Gupta empire]]s,&lt;ref name=&quot;Dyson2018-16b&quot;&gt;
{{citation
|last=Dyson|first=Tim|title=A Population History of India: From the First Modern People to the Present Day|url=https://books.google.com/books?id=3TRtDwAAQBAJ&amp;pg=PA16|year=2018|publisher=Oxford University Press|isbn=978-0-19-882905-8|page=16-17}} Quote: &quot;Magadha power came to extend over the main cities and communication routes of the Ganges basin. Then, under Chandragupta Maurya (c.321–297 bce), and subsequently Ashoka his grandson, Pataliputra became the centre of the loose-knit Mauryan ‘Empire’ which during Ashoka’s reign (c.268–232 bce) briefly had a presence throughout the main urban centres and arteries of the subcontinent, except for the extreme south.&quot;&lt;/ref&gt;&lt;ref name=&quot;Fisher2018-67&quot;&gt;{{citation|last=Fisher|first=Michael H.|title=An Environmental History of India: From Earliest Times to the Twenty-First Century|url=https://books.google.com/books?id=kZVuDwAAQBAJ&amp;pg=PA67|year=2018|publisher=Cambridge University Press|isbn=978-1-107-11162-2|pages=67–}} Quote: &quot;Despite military pressures from within and without India, the Guptas eventually built an empire that, at its peak, stretched as far west as the Indus River​ and as far south as ​Kanchipuram.​ Even in the Gangetic plain,​ however, most of this vast territory territory was ruled by largely autonomous kings who nominally recognized or just paid tribute to the Gupta emperor.&quot;
&lt;/ref&gt;&lt;ref name=&quot;Robb2011&quot;&gt;{{citation|last=Robb|first=Peter|title=A History of India|url=https://books.google.com/books?id=GQ-2VH1LO_EC&amp;pg=PA56|year=2011|publisher=Macmillan |isbn=978-0-230-34549-2|pages=56–57}} Quote: &quot;The Guptas took advantage of an accretion of local power after 320 CE, with the rise of Chandragupta I in Magadha. An empire was established by his successor Sumadra Gupta (r. 335-76). He subdued smaller kingdoms across north India, including much of Bengal, and achieved some kind of suzerainty or influence as far west as the Indus river, and over most of central and eastern India, as far south as Kanchi. His son Chandragupta II (r. about 376-415) also subdued the Shakas in western India. Nevertheless the Gupta empire remained more of a confederacy than a centralized state. By around 550 it had succumbed to invaders (the Hunas, ...), local insurrections, and the collapse of tributary alliances.&quot; 
&lt;/ref&gt;&lt;ref name=&quot;Ludden2013-29&quot;&gt;
{{citation
|last=Ludden
|first=David|title=India and South Asia: A Short History|url=https://books.google.com/books?id=EbFHAQAAQBAJ&amp;pg=PA29|year=2013|publisher=Oneworld Publications|isbn=978-1-78074-108-6|pages=29-30}} Quote: &quot;The geography of the Mauryan Empire resembled a spider with a small dense body and long spindly legs. The highest echelons of imperial society lived in the inner circle composed of the ruler, his immediate family, other relatives, and close allies, who formed a dynastic core. Outside the core, empire travelled stringy routes dotted with armed cities. Outside the palace, in the capital cities, the highest ranks in the imperial elite were held by military commanders whose active loyalty and success in war determined imperial fortunes. Wherever these men failed or rebelled, dynastic power crumbled. ... Imperial society flourished where elites mingled; they were its backbone, its strength was theirs. Kautilya’s ''Arthasastra'' indicates that imperial power was concentrated in its original heartland, in old ''Magadha'', where key institutions seem to have survived for about seven hundred years, down to the age of the Guptas. Here, Mauryan officials ruled local society, but not elsewhere. In provincial towns and cities, officials formed a top layer of royalty; under them, old conquered royal families were not removed, but rather subordinated. In most ''janapadas'', the Mauryan Empire consisted of strategic urban sites connected loosely to vast hinterlands through lineages and local elites who were there when the Mauryas arrived and were still in control when they left.&quot;
&lt;/ref&gt; their collective time span suffused with wide-ranging creativity,&lt;ref name=&quot;Ludden2013-28&quot;&gt;
{{citation
|last=Ludden
|first=David|title=India and South Asia: A Short History|url=https://books.google.com/books?id=EbFHAQAAQBAJ&amp;pg=PA28|year=2013|publisher=Oneworld Publications|isbn=978-1-78074-108-6|pages=28-29}}Quote: &quot;A creative explosion in all the arts was a most remarkable feature of this ancient transformation, a permanent cultural legacy. Mauryan territory was created in its day by awesome armies and dreadful war, but future generations would cherish its beautiful pillars, inscriptions, coins, sculptures, buildings, ceremonies, and texts, particularly later Buddhist writers.&quot;
&lt;/ref&gt;&lt;ref name=&quot;GlickLivesey2014&quot;&gt;{{citation|author=Glenn Van Brummelen|editor=Thomas F. Glick, Steven Livesey, Faith Wallis|title=Medieval Science, Technology, and Medicine: An Encyclopedia|url=https://books.google.com/books?id=77y2AgAAQBAJ&amp;pg=PA46|year=2014|publisher=Routledge|isbn=978-1-135-45932-1|pages=46–48|chapter=Arithmetic}} Quote: &quot;The story of the growth of arithmetic from the ancient inheritance to the wealth passed on to the Renaissance is dramatic and passes through several cultures. The most groundbreaking achievement was the evolution of a positional number system, in which the position of a digit within a number determines its value according to powers (usually) of ten (e.g., in 3,285, the &quot;2&quot; refers to hundreds). Its extension to include decimal fractions and the procedures that were made possible by its adoption transformed the abilities of all who calculated, with an effect comparable to the modern invention of the electronic computer. Roughly speaking, this began in India, was transmitted to Islam, and then to the Latin West.&quot;
&lt;/ref&gt; but also with the declining status of women, ...&quot;&lt;ref name=&quot;Dyson2018-20&quot;&gt;
{{citation
|last=Dyson|first=Tim|title=A Population History of India: From the First Modern People to the Present Day|url=https://books.google.com/books?id=3TRtDwAAQBAJ&amp;pg=PA20|year=2018|publisher=Oxford University Press|isbn=978-0-19-882905-8|pages=20}} 
Quote: &quot;Therefore, by the time of the Mauryan Empire the position of women in mainstream Indo-Aryan society seems to have deteriorated. Customs such as child marriage and dowry were becoming entrenched; and a young women’s purpose in life was to provide sons for the male lineage into which she married. To quote the Arthashāstra: ‘wives are there for having sons’. Practices such as female infanticide and the neglect of young girls were possibly also developing at this time, especially among higher caste people. Further, due to the increasingly hierarchical nature of the society, marriage was possibly becoming an even more crucial institution for childbearing and the formalization of relationships between groups. In turn, this may have contributed to the growth of increasingly instrumental attitudes towards women and girls (who moved home at marriage). It is important to note that, in all likelihood, these developments did not affect people living in large parts of the subcontinent—such as those in the south, and tribal communities inhabiting the forested hill and plateau areas of central and eastern India. That said, these deleterious features have continued to blight Indo-Aryan speaking areas of the subcontinent until the present day.&quot;
&lt;/ref&gt;&lt;ref name=&quot;Stein2010-90&quot;&gt;{{citation|last=Stein|first=Burton|title=A History of India|url=https://books.google.com/books?id=QY4zdTDwMAQC&amp;pg=PA90|year=2010|publisher=John Wiley &amp; Sons|isbn=978-1-4443-2351-1|pages=90–}} 
Quote: &quot;STATUS OF WOMEN DECLINES: Darkness can be said to have pervaded one aspect of society during the inter-imperial centuries: the degradation of women. ... The positions taken and the practices discussed by Manu and the other commentators and writers of dharmashastra are not quaint relics of the distant past, but alive and recurrent in India today – as the attempts to revive the custom of sati (widow immolation) in recent decades has shown. Child marriage, forced marriage, dowry and the expectation of abject wifely subservience, too, have enjoyed lengthy duration and continuity and are proving very difficult to stamp out.&quot;
&lt;/ref&gt;&lt;ref name=&quot;RamusackSievers1999&quot;&gt;{{citation|last=Ramusack|first=Barbara N.|editor=Barbara N. Ramusack, Sharon L. Sievers|title=Women in Asia: Restoring Women to History|url=https://books.google.com/books?id=CNi9Jc22OHsC&amp;pg=PA27|year=1999|publisher=Indiana University Press|isbn=0-253-21267-7|pages=27–29|chapter=Women in South Asia}} Quote: &quot;The legal rights, as well as the ideal images, of women were increasingly circumscribed during the Gupta era. The Laws of Manu, compiled from about 200 to 400 C.E., came to be the most prominent evidence that this era was not necessarily a golden age for women. Through a combination of legal injunctions and moral prescriptions, women were firmly tied to the patriarchal family, ... Thus the Laws of Manu severely reduced the property rights of women, recommended a significant difference in ages between husband and wife and the relatively early marriage of women, and banned widow remarriage. Manu's preoccupation with chastity reflected possibly a growing concern for the maintenance of inheritance rights in the male line, a fear of women undermining the increasingly rigid caste divisions, and a growing emphasis on male asceticism as a higher spiritual calling.&quot;
&lt;/ref&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; I'm on vacation.  Responding because I received an email.  I won't be here to respond to more irrelevant points.  [[User:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#B8860B&quot;&gt;Fowler&amp;amp;fowler&lt;/span&gt;]][[User talk:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#708090&quot;&gt;«Talk»&lt;/span&gt;]] 05:27, 16 October 2019 (UTC)
{{reflist-talk}}

== RfC on superlatives sentence ==

Which of the following sentences should be used as the second sentence of this article?
*'''Option A''' (status quo): {{tq|It is the [[List of countries and dependencies by area|seventh-largest]] country by area, the [[List of countries and dependencies by population|second-most populous]] country, and the most populous [[democracy]] in the world.}}
*'''Option B''': {{tq|It is the [[List of countries and dependencies by population|second-most populous]] country, the most populous [[democracy]], and the [[List of countries and dependencies by area|seventh-largest]] country by area.}}
*'''Option C''': {{tq|It is the [[List of countries and dependencies by population|second-most populous]] country, the [[List of countries and dependencies by area|seventh-largest]] by area, and the most populous [[democracy]] in the world.}}
[[User:Sdkb|Sdkb]] ([[User talk:Sdkb|talk]]) 23:52, 20 October 2019 (UTC)
=== Comments ===
*'''Comment''' Discussion so far on this issue can be found above on this talk page [[Talk:India#Reordering_superlatives_sentence|here]]. In a nutshell: {{u|Bharatiya29}} and I argued that options B or C help emphasize what makes India unique and important by placing them first; {{u|Fowler&amp;fowler}} and {{u|DreamLinker}} argued that there exists some precedent for listing area before population. [[User:Sdkb|Sdkb]] ([[User talk:Sdkb|talk]]) 23:59, 20 October 2019 (UTC)
* '''Option A''' (status quo): It is the normal order and it is right for emphasis at the end, as I have already noted in the above discussion. -- [[User:Kautilya3|Kautilya3]] ([[User talk:Kautilya3|talk]]) 16:30, 23 October 2019 (UTC)
* '''Option A, though the difference is trivial and any of the options presented might suit.''' Honestly, I'm a little surprised that this couldn't be resolved short of RfC with someone just giving way, but seeing as input is being sought, I think any of the options is viable, but the difference between the options is slight enough that we might as well adopt the status quo version. For that matter, I will say that there is a certain kind of conceptual continuity to the order presented in this option (a purely geographic distinction, a geographic and demographic distinction, and then a purely demographic distinction).  I'm not entirely sure Sdkb means when they say that the other two options better emphasize what makes India &quot;unique&quot;, but it seems to me that is going to be a highly subjective thing at the end of the day, and hard to determine through any application of [[WP:WEIGHT]] as this project approaches it.  By the same token, I'm not sure if there is a real strong tendency in other articles to which we can easily point as an empirical matter, if that is indeed an argument advanced by others--in any event, I'm pretty sure we do not have policy or even style guidance on the point to codify any community consensus on the point. Taking this all together, I'm inclined to go with the current version as a perfectly reasonable option and the one I think I probably would have slightly leaned towards myself, had I composed the initial prose here. [[WP:STYLEVAR]] is also arguably at least somewhat relevant here. ''[[User:Snow Rise|&lt;b style=&quot;color: #19a0fd;&quot;&gt;S&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b style=&quot;color: #66c0fd&quot;&gt;n&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b style=&quot;color: #99d5fe;&quot;&gt;o&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b style=&quot;color: #b2dffe;&quot;&gt;w&lt;/b&gt;]] [[User talk:Snow Rise|&lt;sup&gt;&lt;b style=&quot;color: #d4143a&quot;&gt;let's rap&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;]]'' 04:10, 24 October 2019 (UTC)
* '''A or C''', No strong preference between the 2, but I oppose B. I'd prefer it if the &quot;most populous democracy&quot; line was part of a separate sentence. There's no reason to bundle this subjective section over the objective area and total population statistics. [[User:Iffy|Iffy]]★[[User Talk:Iffy|Chat]] -- 09:42, 24 October 2019 (UTC)
*'''Option A''' the status quo makes most sense to me, but all of these are relatively acceptable. [[User:SportingFlyer|SportingFlyer]] ''&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:small; vertical-align:top;&quot;&gt;[[User talk:SportingFlyer|T]]&lt;/span&gt;''·''&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:small; vertical-align:bottom;&quot;&gt;[[Special:Contributions/SportingFlyer|C]]&lt;/span&gt;'' 05:46, 28 October 2019 (UTC)
*'''Option C.''' The first two facts are what make India special; it has not always been a democracy; in fact, it's relatively recently that it became so. [[User:BeenAroundAWhile|BeenAroundAWhile]] ([[User talk:BeenAroundAWhile|talk]]) 14:49, 2 November 2019 (UTC)
*'''Option A''', Looks good to me. -- [[User:CptViraj|&lt;font color=&quot;black&quot;&gt;'''CptViraj'''&lt;/font&gt;]]  ([[User talk:CptViraj|📧]]) 17:09, 2 November 2019 (UTC)
*'''Option C''' states two easily verified &quot;hard&quot; facts first, the more remarkable one first, those two facts combined speaking to the fertility of the area. While I'm more aware that India is considered the &quot;second most populous democracy&quot; than that it's the seventh largest geographically, that is more of an arbitrary statistic: what constitutes a democracy? [[User:Dhtwiki|Dhtwiki]] ([[User talk:Dhtwiki|talk]]) 21:55, 2 November 2019 (UTC)
*'''Option A''' - the status quo makes the most sense atleast to me anyway. –[[User:Davey2010|&lt;span style=&quot;color:blue;&quot;&gt;'''Davey'''&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:orange;&quot;&gt;'''2010'''&lt;/span&gt;]]&lt;sup&gt;[[User talk:Davey2010|&lt;span style=&quot;color:navy;&quot;&gt;'''Talk'''&lt;/span&gt;]]&lt;/sup&gt; 20:26, 3 November 2019 (UTC)
*'''Option B''' It's very subjective but I think B makes the most sense. &lt;small&gt;([[WP:Feedback request service|Summoned by bot]])&lt;/small&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nowrap&quot; style=&quot;font-family:copperplate gothic light;&quot;&gt;[[User:Chris troutman|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#345&quot;&gt;Chris Troutman&lt;/span&gt;]] ([[User talk:Chris troutman|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#345&quot;&gt;talk&lt;/span&gt;]])&lt;/span&gt; 19:10, 4 November 2019 (UTC)
*'''Option A''' - starting with size and then, the population, makes sense to me. [[User:Peter K Burian|Peter K Burian]] ([[User talk:Peter K Burian|talk]]) 14:05, 11 November 2019 (UTC)
*'''Option A''' Keep the original version. [[User:Darwin Naz|Darwin Naz]] ([[User talk:Darwin Naz|talk]]) 23:21, 30 October 2019 (UTC)  (copied from an earlier section where the user had posted erroneously.  Copied by [[User:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#B8860B&quot;&gt;Fowler&amp;amp;fowler&lt;/span&gt;]][[User talk:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#708090&quot;&gt;«Talk»&lt;/span&gt;]] 03:37, 12 November 2019 (UTC))
*'''Option C''', then A, oppose B. A makes sense if you want to start with the size first then population second, but C also makes sense if &quot;second-most populous&quot; is more remarkable/notable than &quot;seventh-largest by area&quot; and should be listed first. I'm leaning towards Option C. [[User:Someone963852|Someone963852]] ([[User talk:Someone963852|talk]]) 00:18, 14 November 2019 (UTC)
*'''Option C'''. I think it makes the most sense to list the population first followed by the area. The bit about Democracy belongs at the end. [[User:AlexEng|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#00C5CD&quot;&gt;'''Alex'''&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#9CBA7F&quot;&gt;'''Eng'''&lt;/span&gt;]]&lt;sup&gt;&lt;small style=&quot;font-size:80%;&quot;&gt;([[User_talk:AlexEng|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#FF83FA&quot;&gt;TALK&lt;/span&gt;]])&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; 00:24, 16 November 2019 (UTC)
*&lt;strike&gt;'''Option C'''&lt;/strike&gt;: Option A is perfect and nice end of sentence.[[User:Rocky 734|Rocky 734]] ([[User talk:Rocky 734|talk]]) 00:49, 16 November 2019 (UTC)
::{{ping|Rocky 734}} Do you mean &quot;Option C&quot; or &quot;Option A?&quot;  [[User:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#B8860B&quot;&gt;Fowler&amp;amp;fowler&lt;/span&gt;]][[User talk:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#708090&quot;&gt;«Talk»&lt;/span&gt;]] 00:29, 19 November 2019 (UTC)
:::*'''Option A''',Sorry option A.[[User:Rocky 734|Rocky 734]] ([[User talk:Rocky 734|talk]]) 01:07, 19 November 2019 (UTC)
*'''Comment''' {{ping|Sdkb}} It is over three weeks now. Those editors who have kindly taken the time to add their comments here have given no evidence for a consensus for change.  The wording has stood in the page for upward of ten years. I might add that the India page is one of the most-edited pages on Wikipedia.  It is the oldest country [[WP:FA]] on Wikipedia, and the most viewed.  It has over 4,000 watchers.  Most regulars on this page have not bothered to weigh in at this RfC. The [[India]] page went through an FAR in 2011, a [[WP:TFA]] appearance on 2 October 2019, in the preparation leading to which dozens of editors contributed to the discussion on this talk page in August and September, and which was finally copy edited by Twofingered Typist, the coordinator of Wikipedia's Guild of Copy Editors. No one in this long stretch of time, over hundreds of discussions, has ever uttered a peep about the order of the characterizations in the lead sentence.  That silent majority unrepresented here counts as well.  Thanks for your contribution to discussion on this talk page, but please request an uninvolved administrator to close the RfC.    Best regards, [[User:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#B8860B&quot;&gt;Fowler&amp;amp;fowler&lt;/span&gt;]][[User talk:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#708090&quot;&gt;«Talk»&lt;/span&gt;]] 20:21, 18 November 2019 (UTC)
::Um, you don't get to just inflate your preferred side's !vote total by claiming a silent majority; that's not at all how this works. Looking at the counts, we have 7 editors expressing a preference for listing area first and 7 (including my own preference for '''Option B or C''') for population first, with a slight trend toward the latter. I had taken this page off my watchlist, so I'm surprised to see this discussion still going on, but it's worth remembering that we're talking about reordering a single sentence. Your behavior above and here suggests to me that you may want to take [[WP:OWNERSHIP]] more to heart. [[User:Sdkb|Sdkb]] ([[User talk:Sdkb|talk]]) 21:34, 18 November 2019 (UTC)
:::Dear {{ping|Sdkb}}, you made your first edit on the [[India]] page when it appeared as a [[WP:TFA]] on 2 October 2019 by changing the characterizations of India in the lead sentence.  (The lead sentence in [[India]] has three descriptions, &quot;seventh-largest country by area,&quot; &quot;the second most populous country,&quot; and the &quot;most populous democracy in the world,&quot; in that order.) Your edit was reverted. The following day, you made a [https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Talk:India&amp;oldid=926814080#Reordering_superlatives_sentence post on this talk page].  This garnered little support for your point of view in the ensuing discussion over several weeks.  Without making a second post in that discussion, or sounding out the editors at the India Project Page, [[WT:INDIA]], you began an RfC on this talk page on 20 October 2019.  In its statement, you offered the readers only three of the six [[permutation]]s (please see the accompanying diagram) of a 3-element set.  It is now nearly a month.  There are ten editors who have expressed a preference for option A, including {{u|DreamLinker}} and me; in that group, there is only one who has effectively voted twice by voting &quot;A OR C&quot;  There are three who have expressed a preference for option B, including {{u|Bharatiya29}} and you who have voted &quot;B OR C,&quot; both of which I am counting.  There are seven editors who have expressed a preference for option C, including, again,  {{u|Bharatiya29}} and you who have voted, &quot;C OR B,&quot; again, both of which I am counting.  One editor {{u|Rocky 734}} has made an ambivalent vote and I have queried him. Again, the count is 10 for A, 3 for B, and 6 for C, pending clarification of one vote.  How is this an example of my ownership, when you began an RfC and took it off your watchlist. You are not required to keep it on your watchlist, of course, it might be even seen as ultimate abnegation, but this page sees a lot of random, drive-by, edits, and dangling RfCs are not good for it. 
::::{{ping|Sdkb}} In light of {{u|Rocky 734}}'s clarification, there are 11 votes for option A (the status quo), 3 for option B, and 6 for option C.  Best regards, [[User:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#B8860B&quot;&gt;Fowler&amp;amp;fowler&lt;/span&gt;]][[User talk:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#708090&quot;&gt;«Talk»&lt;/span&gt;]] 01:12, 19 November 2019 (UTC)  
:::Pinging admins {{ping|Doug Weller}}, {{ping|MilborneOne}}, {{ping|Vanamonde93}}, {{ping|RegentsPark}}, as well as uninvolved ones {{ping|SlimVirgin}}, {{ping|Bishonen}}, {{ping|Dbachman}}, as well as FAC coordinators (as this is an FA)  {{ping|Laser brain}}, {{ping|Ealdgyth}}, as well as {{ping|Dank}} (as this was a recent TFA). I'm on vacation, and I need some advice.  [[User:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#B8860B&quot;&gt;Fowler&amp;amp;fowler&lt;/span&gt;]][[User talk:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#708090&quot;&gt;«Talk»&lt;/span&gt;]] 00:29, 19 November 2019 (UTC)
*It looks like the status quo has consensus. Presumably an uninvolved editor will close this RfC now that a month has gone by. --[[User:RegentsPark|regentspark]] &lt;small&gt;([[User talk:RegentsPark|comment]])&lt;/small&gt; 01:14, 21 November 2019 (UTC)

== Green Area on Globe Discuss ==

&quot;Area controlled by India shown in dark green;
regions claimed but not controlled shown in light green&quot; you have written this... But now light green area is also controlled by Indian Government by revoking article 370 from Jammu and Kashmir... Please colour all area in dark green. [[User:Imvivekchaudhary007|Imvivekchaudhary007]] ([[User talk:Imvivekchaudhary007|talk]]) 01:08, 22 October 2019 (UTC)
:Light green areas are Pakistan administered Kashmir and China administered Aksai Chin.--[[User:DreamLinker|DreamLinker]] ([[User talk:DreamLinker|talk]]) 03:09, 22 October 2019 (UTC)

== India's historical genius and super power status in the ancient and medieval world ==

Can we please add some sections or allow adding them with following subsections

* India's scientific, literary, medical and religious contributions and their significance in the modern world
  * e.g. first true university was established which accommodated pupils from across the Asian and other regions
  * First formal treatise in grammatical linguistics was written in Sanskrit which paved the way for major academic work in other world languages

* India was military super power in 1st millennium with its cultural influence spreading in most of central and south Asia.

* India's contributions in mathematics
 * positional value system was conceived and operational in India which lead to use of 0 (decimal zero)
 * close to accurate earlieestf approximations of Earth's circumference and astronomical observations with regards to planetary system with Sun being at the center and other planets revolving around.
 * Earliest conceptualization of quadratic inequalities and roots using '''Dharacharya method'''
 * Faster approaches for complex calculations with lesser steps required than present in modern day mathematics.

* First soap opera and classical plays were written in India in Sanskrit by '''Kalidas''' who was the greatest poet of his time only to be matched later by the likes of Shaeksepere and Wordsworth among western poets.

* India was the richest country until end of 17 century.

'''Despite western beliefs and history written by contemporary western historians, large part of India was always free and was flourishing in terms of cultural advancement and scientific way of thinking. The British and other colonial powers had influence only in smaller coastal areas where they had managed to be in peaceful nexus with local landlords or rulers. Indian subcontinent in its entirety was never part of any empire. By the end of circa 1000 AD, Indian western frontiers were the only regions in Asia which had successfully reciprocated Islam's spread for many centuries in India.'''

''Also despite popular belief and literature about the effects of non-violent methods, its was the successful armed resistance which effectively routed the British out of India in 1st half of 20th century. The leading figures behind the armed but still patriotic resistance were Subhash Chandra Bose, Bhagat Singh, Chadra Shekhar Azad, Ashfaq Ullah Khan and many other freedom fighters whose efforts paved the way for formal declaration of Indian control over coastal regions which were arguably under any colonial influence.
''

Can we also add some better images under culture and costume as the one currently there don't reflect the modern way of living in India.  &lt;!-- Template:Unsigned --&gt;&lt;small class=&quot;autosigned&quot;&gt;—&amp;nbsp;Preceding [[Wikipedia:Signatures|unsigned]] comment added by [[User:Sin nitins|Sin nitins]] ([[User talk:Sin nitins#top|talk]] • [[Special:Contributions/Sin nitins|contribs]]) 00:33, 26 October 2019 (UTC)&lt;/small&gt; &lt;!--Autosigned by SineBot--&gt;
:Please note that this article is about the Republic of India, the national entity created after the partition of India in 1947. This is also a summary article. Historical detail for the pre-1947 India should go in [[History of India]]. Also note that you need to provide academic [[WP:RS|reliable sources]] for any historical claims that both back up the claims and assert that they are mainstream ones (i.e., they are accepted without controversy by the academic community). --[[User:RegentsPark|regentspark]] &lt;small&gt;([[User talk:RegentsPark|comment]])&lt;/small&gt; 11:20, 26 October 2019 (UTC)
::Republic of India was actually a successor of Union of India which is an infant political nationstate per establishment, not  in terms of history. Predessor civilizations on national territory or historical expansions of their indigenous culture &amp; political hold of countries, are mentioned in their history sections. This main article has brief summaries of Indian Dominion, British India and even medieval and Vedic eras. Even this article isn't an exception. As there is no other country called India, I don't think there will be any controversy adding same. [[History of India]] is relevant section for same but per notability, some more of notable aspects are supposed to be added in summarised history we have on the main article. '''[[User:Aman.kumar.goel|Aman Kumar Goel]]'''&lt;sup&gt;(''[[User talk:Aman.kumar.goel|Talk]]'')&lt;/sup&gt; 16:37, 28 October 2019 (UTC)
::::&gt;&gt;&gt;&quot;Also despite popular belief and literature about the effects of non-violent methods, its was the successful armed resistance which effectively routed the British out of India in 1st half of 20th century.&quot;  Really it was?  The prime minister of the United Kingdom, Clement Attlee, must have been out of his mind, when on the evening of 30 January 1948 he broadcast on behalf of the British government and people from London, and among other things said, &quot;For a quarter of a century this one man has been the major factor in every consideration of the Indian problem.&quot;  (hear at the 1:00 mark in [https://www.cbc.ca/archives/entry/india-the-assassination-of-mahatma-gandhi this audio, &quot;Assassination of Mahatma Gandhi,&quot; from the Canadian Broadcasting Corporation]) You seriously want to waste our time?  [[User:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#B8860B&quot;&gt;Fowler&amp;amp;fowler&lt;/span&gt;]][[User talk:Fowler&amp;amp;fowler|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#708090&quot;&gt;«Talk»&lt;/span&gt;]] 03:52, 12 November 2019 (UTC)

==Out of africa theory is a THEORY==
{{resolved}}-WP:NOTFORUM
remove that modern humans settled in India from Africa 55000 years ago. The OOAT is not proven and is still a theory.  &lt;!-- Template:Unsigned IP --&gt;&lt;small class=&quot;autosigned&quot;&gt;—&amp;nbsp;Preceding [[Wikipedia:Signatures|unsigned]] comment added by [[Special:Contributions/190.98.102.219|190.98.102.219]] ([[User talk:190.98.102.219#top|talk]]) 16:52, 2 November 2019 (UTC)&lt;/small&gt; &lt;!--Autosigned by SineBot--&gt;
:Please read the second paragraph [[Scientific theory|here]]; it explains very succinctly why your understanding of the terminology is incorrect. &lt;span style=&quot;font-family:Papyrus&quot;&gt;[[User:Vanamonde93|Vanamonde]] ([[User Talk:Vanamonde93|Talk]])&lt;/span&gt; 19:15, 4 November 2019 (UTC)
::[[Talk:India/Archive 46#Remove out of Africa THEORY]].--&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight:bold;color:darkblue&quot;&gt;[[User_talk:Moxy|Moxy]]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;color:red&quot;&gt;🍁&lt;/span&gt; 00:09, 5 November 2019 (UTC)

== Extended-confirmed-protected edit request on 7 November 2019 ==

{{edit extended-protected|India|answered=yes}}
In the right box, change &quot;Official Languages TO Union Languages&quot;. And, change &quot;Recognised regional languages TO Official Languages&quot;. Hindi and English are not the only official languages, it is only used in the Union and it does not mean they are the only Official languages. When we search in google, it lists wikipedia content as the top search and says there are only two official languages in India - which is entirely misleading. [[User:Aru8|Aru8]] ([[User talk:Aru8|talk]]) 18:13, 7 November 2019 (UTC)
:[[File:Red information icon with gradient background.svg|20px|link=|alt=]] '''Not done:''' please provide [[Wikipedia:Reliable sources|reliable sources]] that support the change you want to be made.&lt;!-- Template:EEp --&gt; [[User:Eggishorn|Eggishorn]] [[User talk:Eggishorn|(talk)]] [[Special:Contributions/Eggishorn|(contrib)]] 19:52, 7 November 2019 (UTC)

Please refer this link stating that Hindi and English are only used in the union.
https://knowindia.gov.in/profile/the-union/official-language.php
You can refer the below link for the list of languages recognized as Official langugages.
https://mhrd.gov.in/sites/upload_files/mhrd/files/upload_document/languagebr.pdf  &lt;!-- Template:Unsigned --&gt;&lt;small class=&quot;autosigned&quot;&gt;—&amp;nbsp;Preceding [[Wikipedia:Signatures|unsigned]] comment added by [[User:Aru8|Aru8]] ([[User talk:Aru8#top|talk]] • [[Special:Contributions/Aru8|contribs]]) 07:14, 8 November 2019 (UTC)&lt;/small&gt; &lt;!--Autosigned by SineBot--&gt;
:{{u|Aru8}}, you need to reset the request to unanswered for it to be reactivated again. Note that searching the talk page archives for &quot;language&quot;, &quot;official&quot; and &quot;national&quot; gives multiple discussions on the issue. This is one of the best and most rigorously maintained article on Wikipedia, so it is unlikely that a simple edit request will get anywhere. Unless it was just an oversight which I find quite unlikely, you need to go over the previous discussions on the subject in the archives, and bring something new to the table, and try and convince the principal contributors of the article. Just a heads up, I don't have the expertise to say whether the links you've given does that. &lt;b&gt;[[User:Usedtobecool|&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b9272b&quot;&gt;Usedtobecool&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;]]&amp;nbsp;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;small&gt;[[User talk:Usedtobecool|&lt;span style=&quot;color:#080&quot;&gt;TALK&lt;/span&gt;]]&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;nbsp;[[Special:Contributions/Usedtobecool|✨]]&lt;/b&gt; 11:21, 8 November 2019 (UTC)

The Indo-European languages are a language family of several hundred related languages and dialects. &lt;!-- Template:Unsigned IP --&gt;&lt;small class=&quot;autosigned&quot;&gt;—&amp;nbsp;Preceding [[Wikipedia:Signatures|unsigned]] comment added by [[Special:Contributions/122.163.79.233|122.163.79.233]] ([[User talk:122.163.79.233#top|talk]]) 06:48, 25 November 2019 (UTC)&lt;/small&gt;
:Yes, you've &quot;quoted&quot; the first sentence of [[:Indo-European languages]]... Was there some particular point concerning that, and related to this article, which you wanted to make? --&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:Arial;font-weight:bold;color:#004d80;&quot;&gt; [[User talk:Begoon|Begoon]]&lt;/span&gt; 09:14, 25 November 2019 (UTC)

== Extended-confirmed-protected edit request on 26 November 2019 ==

{{edit extended-protected|India|answered=yes}}
India is one of the first Civilizations which emerged in the planet, it is contemporary to China and fertile crescent, called as Indus Valley today, Modern Indians share same genetic history to them{{Citation|title=Indus valley from basis of Modern Indian DNA.|url=https://www.sciencemag.org/news/2019/09/genome-nearly-5000-year-old-woman-links-modern-indians-ancient-civilization}}, and Indus people form basis of Modern Indian DNA, Indus Culture brought earliest form of Hindu or Sanatana Dharma, Sari and other ancient clothing, Cotton farming, Yoga, Terracotta. I know that Indus Script is yet to be deciphered but it has proven connection to Dravidians/South India. [[User:Sagnique|Sagnique]] ([[User talk:Sagnique|talk]]) 02:35, 26 November 2019 (UTC)
:[[File:Red question icon with gradient background.svg|20px|link=|alt=]] '''Not done:''' it's not clear what changes you want to be made. Please mention the specific changes in a &quot;change X to Y&quot; format and provide a [[Wikipedia:Reliable sources|reliable source]] if appropriate.&lt;!-- Template:EEp --&gt; – [[User:Jonesey95|Jonesey95]] ([[User talk:Jonesey95|talk]]) 02:56, 26 November 2019 (UTC)

== [[bhaona]]  ==

As mentioned in the ''Performing arts and media'' section, the [[bhaona]] of Assam is often &quot;based on Hindu mythology, but also borrowing from medieval romances or social and political events&quot;. &quot;It is a traditional form of entertainment, with religious messages, prevalent is [[Assam|Assam, India]]. It is a creation of [[Srimanta Sankardev|Mahapurusha Srimanta Sankardeva]], written in the early sixteenth century. He created the form to convey religious messages to villagers through entertainment. Later [[Madhavdeva|Srimanta Madhavdeva]]&lt;nowiki/&gt;also wrote some plays. The plays of bhaona are popularly known as [[Ankiya Nat|Ankiya Nats]] and their staging is known as bhaona. Bhaona is generally staged at [[Satra (Ekasarana Dharma)|xatras]] and [[Namghar|namghars]] in Assam. There are some special characteristics of Bhaona like the plays, dialogues, costumes, ornaments, entry and foot-steps of the characters. These characteristics helps to differentiate Bhaona from other plays.&quot; Therefore it should be included in the mentioned section. 
Abhroneel 09:21, 30 November 2019 (UTC)</text>
      <sha1>jeopf9vd1n8td2fj1baxazp1osvsn5f</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>
